<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/Boards/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/Boards/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-05-24T20:57:43-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Boards/</id><title type="html">Simple Boards Devlog</title><subtitle>This blog details the creation of simple boards. The website is based on lolboards. The goal is make me confortable with web development and introduce me to new technologies.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Day 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Boards/2018/05/24/Day-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day 3" /><published>2018-05-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Boards/2018/05/24/Day-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Boards/2018/05/24/Day-3.html">&lt;p&gt;This is actually Day 4. I spent most of Day 3 trying to get the devlog on Github. I thought I had it on Day 2, but the layout wasn’t working. I spent some 3 hours trying various things until I found post saying I had to fix configuration file. It would have been lovely if this was on the Jekyll website, but sometimes you just have to take what you get. Well, that happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began today finishing the boards page. The button’s size should be consistent with the size of posts. The posts also should navigate correctly now; that is, when I set-up the posts page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/WRDQpHd.png&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also began and hopefully finished the sign in page. This was just typical form stuff. It was difficult at all. I followed my page creation plan that I discussed in my previous page. It seemed pretty useful, although, this page is too short to make any final conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only real issue I had was deciding whether I should style the page with mostly with bootstrap’s class configurations or typical CSS. Turns out, this does not really matter since the page is really short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Java UI experience is really coming in handy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ewLe52q.png&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is actually Day 4. I spent most of Day 3 trying to get the devlog on Github. I thought I had it on Day 2, but the layout wasn’t working. I spent some 3 hours trying various things until I found post saying I had to fix configuration file. It would have been lovely if this was on the Jekyll website, but sometimes you just have to take what you get. Well, that happened.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Day 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Boards/2018/05/22/Day-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day 2" /><published>2018-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Boards/2018/05/22/Day-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Boards/2018/05/22/Day-2.html">&lt;p&gt;I have decided to change the scope of the project. Instead of making a website for multiple boards, I will make a single board website with additional pages for registering, logging, creating post, and viewing and replying to posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/cnn25fK.png&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
More progress on main web page has been made. I have decided on a simple theme. The theme consists of a dark background, mostly white text, and splashes of a certain blue. Its screams unprofessional but at least I am trying. Codepen, particularly, has been a lovely visual editor and has made this entire ordeal very relaxing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also adjusted the HTML  layout to better reflect the model, lolboards. This is especially important because it gave me an idea for a systematic way of developing websites. First I describe the data, particularly text and images. I use placeholders if the data is dynamic. Then I use html to position the data. Then CSS. Then Javascript and PHP, if necessary. I hope this will make developing websites easier and faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also decided to start make blog the progress, of which you are reading now. I also wanted to challenge myself and mostly use the command line. First, I installed the Linux subsystem for Windows. I chose the Ubuntu shell because, frankly, it sounds the least annoying.  Next, I installed Git for this subsystem.  I used Git to create a project for this website. I also set up the project page, of which this blog is hosted. Lastly, I installed and set-up Jekyll. I ran into many issues along the way but it everything is currently working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/0tDlKhq.png&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I have decided to change the scope of the project. Instead of making a website for multiple boards, I will make a single board website with additional pages for registering, logging, creating post, and viewing and replying to posts.</summary></entry></feed>